Attention!
I will now explain to you the details
of the Trost Recovery Operation!
Let me start by introducing this fellow!
This is Eren Jaeger,
a member of the Cadets!
He is the successful result
of our top-secret Titan
transformation experiments!
In Titan form, he will lift that
giant rock near the front gate,
carry it to the wrecked gate,
and seal the hole!
As for you,
you're to defend him from the
other Titans while he carries the rock!
Should this operation succeed,
humanity will have taken back land
from the Titans for the very first time!
Indeed, it may
seem extraordinarily small
when compared to what
humanity has given up this far!
However...!
For humankind,
that single, small step...
...will be a great leap forward!
Eren! Don't you recognize me?!
I'm Mikasa!
Part of your family!
Dodge, Ackermann!
What the hell?!
He's just a regular, dumb Titan!
Change of plans!
We're to defend Jaeger from the
other Titans until we can recover him!
He holds a precious chance for humanity.
We can't abandon him just like that!
Where am I?
I'm home...
Jean!
Why isn't he using his ODM gear?!
Oh no!
Don't tell me it's malfunctioning?!
I'll manage somehow!
Mikasa!
What happened to the plan?!
It's failed!
We're fighting because
we can't leave Eren behind!
But there are too many Titans...
At this rate, we'll be wiped out!
From the back of the head
to the nape of the neck...
...1 meter high and
10 centimeters across!
Eren... Answer me...
Even though just one step outside
the wall lies a hellish world...
Why did you want to
venture into the outside world?!
Why?
Because...
...I was born in this world!
Eren!
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
"Primal Desire"
"The Struggle for Trost, Part 9"
Damn... I can't believe I'm
draggin' everyone down...
Will this really work out somehow?
We can't go on, Captain!
It's just us now!
Let's fall back to the rock for now!
Situation report!
Five Titans coming from the gate!
There's no way I can just sit
around and wait until the coast is clear!
Jean!
So his gear is busted!
What's going on?!
Crap!
What the hell?!
Damn it! Of all the times...!
Jean! Stay calm!
Marco!
What are you doing?!
Man!
Don't go causin' trouble for us!
Damn! Why is the trigger so stiff?!
Jean!
Oww!
What are you doing?!
Same to you! Now get outta there!
You guys are damn reckless!
No, you are!
That scared the hell out of me!
Look!
Eren...
Mikasa!
Armin!
Eren prevailed!
He's trying to fulfill
his responsibility now!
Now if we just cover
him until he reaches the gate...
...victory will be ours!
Defend him!
Even if it costs us our lives...
...we must let Eren reach the gate!
Do not let the Titans get near him!
We gotta give Eren backup! Keep 'em off him!
You two head to Eren!
That's an order! Is that clear?!
Yes, Sir!
The Mitabi team!
What are you doing?!
The Titans are ignoring us now!
Our only choice is to get close
enough to grab their attention!
Look this way, damn it!
Or else we'll shove our blades
up your smelly asses and kill you!
--Here they come!
--We got two of 'em!
Run! Run for the buildings!
That's insane!
Setting foot down there is suicide!
And they have no way to
fight without horses or buildings!
No... That's the only option now.
Follow Mitabi Team!
Armin. We need to go, too.
This way!
Come get me!
My body feels...
...like it's about to be crushed into a pulp...
Mikasa... Armin...
What are you doing?
You'll end up Titan food if
you walk around down there...!
C'mon! Hurry this way, you slowpoke!
Come get me!
H-Hey!
Mitabi!
Why did you want
to venture into
the outside world?
From the moment
we're born, we're all...
...free...
Some might try to deny that,
but it doesn't matter how strong they are!
Fiery waters... Lands of ice...
Or whatever else!
Whoever gets to see those things
will have the greatest
freedom this world has to offer!
Fight!
If anything is worth
giving your life, it's that!
It doesn't matter how
terrifying the world may be!
It doesn't matter
how cruel the world may be!
Fight!
There's still a Titan ahead!
I'll handle this!
Out of the way!
Go, Eren!
Fight!
Everyone...
Your deaths weren't in vain...
Today, for the first time in history...
...humanity has beaten the Titans!
Yellow smoke shell spotted!
It seems the operation...
was a success!
Send in additional reinforcements!
Rescue the Elite Squad!
The remaining Titans are coming!
Head up the wall!
I'll withdraw after I've recovered Eren!
Armin! How's Eren?!
He's unbelievably hot to the touch!
We need to hurry...
and get him up the wall...!
Part of his body is fused to it!
--I can't pull him free!
--Then we'll have to cut!
W-Wait! Please!
Eren! Armin!
Mikasa...
Huh?!
Those are...
The wings...
...of freedom...
Hey. You kids.
What exactly is going on here?
Afterward, thanks to the actions
of the Scout Regiment and the
Garrison Regiment's Corps of Engineers,
Wall Rose once
again held the Titans at bay.
Taking out the rest of the Titans
trapped inside Trost took a full day,
during which the wall-mounted
cannons fired nonstop.
Most of the Titans that
had gathered by the wall
were wiped out by explosive shells.
The few that remained were
mostly mopped up by the Scouts.
During this, one 4-meter
Titan and one 7-meter Titan
were successfully captured alive.
However...
207 people were dead or missing,
and 897 were injured.
Although this was the first time
humanity had stopped a Titan invasion,
far too many people had been lost
to celebrate this historic achievement.
Hey...
Are you...
...Marco?
Do you know his name, cadet?
I wondered where he was...
But... he's the last person who would ever...
Marco...
What happened?
D-Did someone--anyone--see
how he went out?
What is his name?
Tell me if you know. Quickly.
Do you understand, cadet?
Two days have passed since
we sealed the hole with the rock.
Yet we still haven't
rounded up all the bodies.
At this rate,
an epidemic could break out.
We must prevent a secondary disaster.
There's no time to lament our
comrades' deaths yet.
Understand?
Member of the 104th Cadet Corps
and Captain of Squad 19...
...Marco Bodt.
Marco.
I'm glad you knew his name.
Let's continue.
What is this...?
Leftover Titan vomit.
Apparently they don't
have digestive systems,
so they puke people out like
that once they've had their fill.
You can't be serious...
Damn... There's no way of
telling who's who in there!
I'm sorry...
It's no use apologizing.
We need to hurry and give them a funeral.
Have any questions?
Commander Erwin, the head of
the Scouts Regiment's Task Force...
...and Captain Levi!
U-Umm...
Where... am I?
It should be obvious.
Let's just say it's a dungeon.
You're currently in the
custody of the Military Police.
Only just now were
we permitted to see you.
That key...!
Yes. It's yours.
I'll return it later.
Dr. Jaeger's basement,
in your home in Shiganshina...
A secret surrounding
the Titans is there, correct?
Yes. I think so.
That's what my father said.
And you've lost your memory,
and your old man's gone missing...
Pretty convenient story, if you ask me.
Levi.
We've already concluded he
has no reason to lie. You know that.
There is still so little we know,
but for now, I feel the most important
thing is to ask about your intentions.
My intentions?
If we want to check out your home,
we'll need to take back
Shiganshina District along Wall Maria.
Sealing the damaged gate there would
be the best way to accomplish that.
Which means we'll need your Titan ability.
Naturally, it's a Titan
that will determine our fate.
The Colossal Titan
and the Armored Titan
most likely work the same way as you.
Your intentions are the key.
The key to saving humankind from this despair.
I'm...
I'm going to drive out...
...every last one from this world!
Hey. Answer the damn question, you twit.
What do you want to do?
I want to join the Scouts...
...and slaughter every Titan I can!
Ah. Not bad.
Erwin. I'll take responsibility for him.
Let the higher-ups know.
I don't necessarily trust him, though.
If he betrays us or goes out of control,
I'll kill him on the spot.
The top brass won't complain.
Because I'm the only one cut out for this.
You're in.
I'll make you a member of the Scouts.
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength--and our weakness--
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
A special court-martial.
After being held in an underground cell,
Eren is dragged into a courthouse
filled with the heads of each regiment.
What happens there will
determine whether he lives or dies.
"Can't Look into His Eyes Yet
Eve of the Counterattack, Part 1"